List<Map<String, dynamic>> dialysisPartOneQuestions = [
  {
    'question':
        'Which of the following is the primary function of a hemodialysis machine?',
    'answers': [
      'Blood pressure monitoring',
      'Fluid balance control',
      'Removing waste products from the blood',
      'Electrolyte supplementation',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'During hemodialysis, which vascular access method provides the highest blood flow rates?',
    'answers': [
      'Arteriovenous graft',
      'Arteriovenous fistula',
      'Tunneled central venous catheter',
      'Peripheral intravenous catheter',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the primary purpose of heparin administration during hemodialysis?',
    'answers': [
      'To reduce pain and discomfort',
      'To prevent clotting of the dialysis machine',
      'To improve blood pressure regulation',
      'To increase calcium levels',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which electrolyte imbalance is commonly associated with end-stage renal disease (ESRD) patients undergoing hemodialysis?',
    'answers': [
      'Hyperkalemia',
      'Hypocalcemia',
      'Hypernatremia',
      'Hypomagnesemia',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'When assessing a patient\'s vascular access site before dialysis, which finding should the nurse be most concerned about?',
    'answers': [
      'Mild erythema',
      'Thrill and bruit',
      'Edema at the site',
      'Skin warmth',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which medication is often administered intravenously to stimulate red blood cell production in dialysis patients with anemia?',
    'answers': ['Epinephrine', 'Erythropoietin', 'Insulin', 'Digoxin',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'During dialysis, which parameter should the nurse closely monitor to prevent complications related to fluid removal?',
    'answers': [
      'Blood pressure',
      'Heart rate',
      'Respiratory rate',
      'Temperature',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the primary goal of peritoneal dialysis?',
    'answers': [
      'To remove waste products from the bloodstream',
      'To promote fluid retention',
      'To maintain vascular access',
      'To filter blood through an artificial kidney machine',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which condition might indicate the need for urgent hemodialysis?',
    'answers': [
      'Mild fatigue',
      'Severe hyperphosphatemia',
      'Elevated blood urea nitrogen (BUN)',
      'Stable potassium levels',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which complication can occur if a patient undergoing hemodialysis has inadequate anticoagulation during the procedure?',
    'answers': ['Hypertension', 'Hemorrhage', 'Hypotension', 'Hypercalcemia',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the purpose of the "dry weight" concept in dialysis care?',
    'answers': [
      'To measure the patient\'s weight without any fluid removal',
      'To determine the patient\'s ideal body weight',
      'To assess the patient\'s hydration status',
      'To calculate the patient\'s dietary intake',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which medication is commonly administered to dialysis patients to control hyperphosphatemia?',
    'answers': ['Calcium carbonate', 'Furosemide', 'Dopamine', 'Epinephrine',],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the primary role of the dialysis nurse during a peritoneal dialysis exchange?',
    'answers': [
      'Monitoring the patient\'s blood pressure',
      'Regulating the dialysate temperature',
      'Assessing the patient\'s vascular access',
      'Ensuring proper positioning of the peritoneal catheter',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which laboratory parameter is essential to monitor in a patient receiving hemodialysis to prevent dialysis-related complications?',
    'answers': [
      'Serum creatinine',
      'Hemoglobin A1c',
      'Serum potassium',
      'Total cholesterol',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'In hemodialysis, which factor is most important in determining the rate of ultrafiltration?',
    'answers': [
      'Blood flow rate',
      'Dialysate flow rate',
      'Patient\'s body weight',
      'Duration of dialysis session',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the primary responsibility of the nurse when a patient experiences hypotension during hemodialysis?',
    'answers': [
      'Administer a hypertonic saline bolus',
      'Increase the dialysate temperature',
      'Reduce the blood flow rate',
      'Elevate the patient\'s legs and notify the healthcare provider',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which type of peritoneal dialysis involves a continuous exchange of dialysate fluid during the day and night?',
    'answers': [
      'Continuous Ambulatory Peritoneal Dialysis (CAPD)',
      'Automated Peritoneal Dialysis (APD)',
      'Intermittent Peritoneal Dialysis (IPD)',
      'Hemodialysis',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the primary advantage of using a catheter with a swan-neck design in peritoneal dialysis?',
    'answers': [
      'It minimizes the risk of infection',
      'It enhances the flow of dialysate',
      'It allows for easy disconnection',
      'It prevents kinking and obstruction',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which medication is commonly prescribed to manage secondary hyperparathyroidism in dialysis patients?',
    'answers': [
      'Calcium gluconate',
      'Calcitriol (Rocaltrol)',
      'Enoxaparin (Lovenox)',
      'Phenytoin (Dilantin)',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'During a peritoneal dialysis assessment, the nurse observes cloudy effluent. What might this indicate?',
    'answers': [
      'A dialysis catheter infection',
      'Adequate dialysis clearance',
      'Normal peritoneal membrane function',
      'Hypovolemia',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which dietary restriction is often necessary for patients on hemodialysis to manage electrolyte imbalances?',
    'answers': ['Low sodium', 'Low protein', 'Low fat', 'Low fiber',],
    'correctIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the primary role of the dialysis nurse when a patient is receiving continuous renal replacement therapy (CRRT)?',
    'answers': [
      'Administering pain medication',
      'Monitoring urine output',
      'Adjusting the dialysate flow rate',
      'Ensuring circuit patency and monitoring vital signs',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which of the following medications is commonly used to treat hyperphosphatemia in dialysis patients?',
    'answers': [
      'Calcium gluconate',
      'Phenytoin (Dilantin)',
      'Sevelamer (Renagel)',
      'Magnesium sulfate',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the purpose of the Kt/V (clearance times time over volume) measurement in dialysis therapy?',
    'answers': [
      'To assess the patient\'s nutritional status',
      'To measure the adequacy of dialysis',
      'To calculate the patient\'s fluid balance',
      'To monitor the patient\'s blood pressure',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'In peritoneal dialysis, which type of dialysate solution contains dextrose and helps remove excess fluid and waste?',
    'answers': [
      'Hypertonic dialysate',
      'Hypotonic dialysate',
      'Isotonic dialysate',
      'Colloidal dialysate',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  }
];
